STEVEN VAN COURT

Coon Rapids, MN 55448

Phone: 715 - 864 - 0930 | Email: <u>Steven.vancourt@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/steven-vancourt-cia-08375263/</u> GitHub: https://github.com/StevenVC-P | Portfolio: stevenvancourt.com

Summary:

Full Stack Developer with one year of programming experience, military background, and audit expertise. Proficient in front-end and back-end coding, with a focus on user-centered design in web development and databases. Adaptable and committed to continuous learning in group projects. Strong communication skills, effectively collaborating with technical and non-technical team members to meet end-user needs.

Technical Skills:

Languages: HTML, CSS, ES6 JavaScript, JAVA, SQL

Frameworks/Libraries: Node.js, Express, React, Jquery, Bootstrap

Tools: MySql, MongoDB, Rest APIs, Axios

Methods: Restful WebServices, Testing, Asynchronous Programming, Pair Programming, Agile methodology

Projects:

ArcaneProxies-

Site: https://arcaneproxy.stevenvancourt.com/ Github:https://github.com/StevenVC-P/MTGCardAlter

Technologies: Express, React, Node.js, Rest APIs, DomtolMAGE, Stability.ai,

Summary: Magic the Gathering Proxy generator with Al art

Technical Responsibilities: Developing both front and back, styling the various types of cards, standardizing text and icons

printed.

Modern Mornings -

Site: http://morning.stevenvancourt.com/ Github:github.com/StevenVC-P/modern_mornings

Technologies: JavaScript, CSS, HTML5, APIs

Summary: Search site, a flexible SPA UX design for Mobile or PC, with API calls to Gnews.lo and Reddit. **Technical Responsibilities:** Set up API call to Gnew.lo, styling news cards, and building a display carousel

Swaps -

Site: https://swaps.stevenvancourt.com Github: github.com/StevenVC-P/swaps

Technologies: React Framework, Bootstrap, Axios, Rest APIs, Mongoose

Summary: High quality social media platform for the zero energy swap enthusiast.

Technical Responsibilities: Created the base components, and the functionality of the comments and filter bar.

Professional Experience:

Software Developer May 2021 - Sep 2023
Optum Minneapolis, MN

- · Worked on the RxComet website, utilizing React, SQL, and Java
- · Completed user stories that enhanced UI and restructured features to allow more flexibility
- · Reconfigure data received from the database and modified API requests sent to ServiceNow

Fraud Analyst Aug 2021 -Feb 2022
Best Buy Minneapolis, MN

• Investigated over 900 refund & reship claims, evaluating potential red flags and refund abusers

Internal Auditor

Jun 2019 – Jan 2021

Christopher & Banks

Plymouth, MN

• Assessed controls over financial reporting, and designed flow charts for financial controls

Consultant Auditor Oct 2018 - May 2019
Wipfli Minneapolis, MN

- Collaborative fast-paced team for one week assignments with different local banks
- · Reviewed banking compliance regulations, catching on average 10 issues per location visited

Volunteer Auditor

Hope Fellowship

Summers 2018 – June 2020

Ramsey, MN

• Evaluated church's financial controls, resulting in 5 recommendations taken up by the board

Auditor Feb 2016 - Oct 2018
Tena Companies Minneapolis, MN

· Analized loan portfolios, identified customer service issues resulting in retraining of staff.

Financial Specialist Feb 2006 – Feb 2012

Roseville, MN

247TH FIN. MINNESOTA NATIONAL GUARD

Trainer/Mentor Jun 2010, Jun 2011

- Provided training and critique of payroll and disbursement processes at annual events **Deployed to Iraq** *Jul* 2007 *Mar* 2008
- Collaborated with a team of 5 analyzing and resolving 20-30 payroll and entitlement issues daily
- Identified 1,000 unauthorized benefit claims and corrected 2000 soldier's unclaimed benefits

Education:

Full Stack Developer - University of Minnesota Certificate - May 2021

A fulltime 12 week intensive program focused on gaining programming skills in JavaScript, Databases, and React

Certified Internal Auditor - Certificate #159480 - Mar 2018

University of Wisconsin-Eau Claire - Sept 2010 - May 2013

Bachelor of Business Administration (B.B.A.) Finance, General

Eagle Scout Award - Sept 2005